<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An exact account of the success of his majesties army in Ireland for the last week; giving a relation of the number killed. Together with a list of the officers names taken prisoners and brought into Dublin. With a description of the train of artillery that is gone to besidge Athlon.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1691</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03152</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3583</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R176809</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52211820</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52211820</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175672</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03152)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175672)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2745:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An exact account of the success of his majesties army in Ireland for the last week; giving a relation of the number killed. Together with a list of the officers names taken prisoners and brought into Dublin. With a description of the train of artillery that is gone to besidge Athlon.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at London ;</pubPlace>
                  <pubPlace>and re-printed at Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>in the year. 1691.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through, tightly bound with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697 --  Campaigns --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691 --  Campaigns --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Athlone (Ireland) --  Siege, 1691 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:175672:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:175672:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <hi>AN EXACT ACCOUNT</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Succeſs of His Majeſties Army in <hi>Ireland</hi> for the laſt Week; Giving a Relation of the number Killed. Together with a Liſt of the Officers Names taken Priſoners and brought <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nto <hi>Dublin.</hi> With a Deſcription of the Train of Artillery that is gone to Beſidge <hi>Athlon.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WE have an Account from <hi>Cor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>,</hi> That on <hi>Friday</hi> laſt Major <hi>Culliford,</hi> with 100 of the Army and 250 of the Mili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tia, went into <hi>Eveleary</hi> on <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Borders of the County of <hi>Kerry,</hi> and killed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Rapparees of <hi>Charles Mac-Curthy</hi> of <hi>Bellea</hi>'s <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>giment and an Officer and burnt the Country: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Iriſh</hi> had notice of their coming, and had <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ve away the prey of the Country, ſo that our <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>n got only thirty Cows, two hundred Sheep, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d about one hundred pounds worth of Lum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>. All the Rapparees of this Country are ſo diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>rſed, that ſcarce 5 are to be found together be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>een <hi>Blarny</hi> and <hi>Bantry,</hi> except in the Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>s and Bogs which are inacceſſible—Upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Expedition of Major <hi>Culliford</hi>'s towards <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rry,</hi> Major <hi>Wade</hi> and the <hi>Bandon</hi> Militia, who <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ent out with him, parting from him at <hi>Mac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>p,</hi> took a conſiderable prey in <hi>Glanacrime,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d killed fourteen Raparees — And on <hi>Sunday</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Collonel <hi>Beecher</hi> Lieutenant Collonel <hi>Moor</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Captain <hi>Bernard,</hi> with the Militia under their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ommand, marched from <hi>Wintervary</hi> into the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>mies Quarters killed between forty and fifty <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>pparees, brought off 1100 head of Black <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ttle, 1200 Sheep, and 100 Garrans and return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to their reſpective Quarters without the leaſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s—We have advice from <hi>Caſhil,</hi> That ſome <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ys ſince, three of Li<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>utenant Collonel <hi>Cleer</hi>'s Militia Troop, and four of his Servants, fell on a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>rcel of Notorious Rapparees, killed two of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>em, brought away their Heads, took ſeveral of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>eir Arms, releaſed two of Collonel <hi>Hale</hi>'s Sol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ers, which theſe Rapparees had taken priſoners, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d recovered their Arms, and likewiſe re-took <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>me proviſions of Bread, which theſe Rappa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>es had a little before ſurpriſed—<hi>Ditto</hi>— <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> dayes after, a party of Lieutenant Collonel <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>er</hi>'s, Major <hi>Green</hi>'s, and Captain <hi>Pennyfed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he</hi>'s Militia Dragoons, to the number of fifty. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>der the Command of Lieutenant <hi>Thomas Prince,</hi> made an Incurſion into the Enemies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>rters, where they met with a party of Rap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ees, killed thirty of them on the place, brought way about thirty Cows and 25 Horſes, and had <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ly one man ſlightly wounded,—By an Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>er Arriv'd from <hi>Kilkenny,</hi> we have the follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>g Relation, that on <hi>Saturday</hi> night laſt the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>pparees came to <hi>Burres</hi> in the County of <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rlough,</hi> and ſtole thence 22 Horſes belonging Captain <hi>Kemiſh</hi>'s Militia Dragoons of that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>unty, ſome of whoſe Dragoons followed them into this County joyned with a party of our Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litia poſted at <hi>Graige,</hi> under Command of Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant <hi>Read,</hi> purſued and overtook them on <hi>Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day</hi> Evening near a Wood-ſide about <hi>Blanch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fields</hi> Park within four Miles of this place, en<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>gaged them, though much above their number and 'tis probable had been worſted their Horſes being wearied in the purſuit) when Quarter-Maſter <hi>Blunt</hi> with 12 of Captain <hi>Mukin</hi>'s Mili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tia Dragoons of this City, coming from <hi>Cather<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lough</hi> (whither he want to Convoy Major <hi>M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>darty</hi> the Generals Son from <hi>Kilkenny</hi>) heard of their Engagment, and broke the Rapparees, who were very advantagiouſly poſted Killed 12 and took 6 Priſoners, among whom were <hi>Derby D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ff Doyl</hi> their Captain a very ſtout Fellow and a great Rapparee, commonly calld Brigader <hi>Doyle Charles Maldick</hi> a <hi>French</hi> Lieutenant in the Lord <hi>Gillways</hi> Regiment, <hi>Doyle</hi> his Brother, Son in Law, and one other, were the next day tryed by a Court Martial, and all ſhot at <hi>Gowran</hi> and their Heads brought to <hi>K<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ny<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> upon the Walls of the City. Pro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ctions were found in moſt of their Pockets and in <hi>Doyles</hi> a Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion from <hi>Sarſfield</hi> to raiſe what Horſes, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cruits he could to bring into <hi>Cannaught</hi> by the 2d of <hi>Jun</hi> in this Action we regained our Horſes, took ſome more and had only one Man wound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, Captain <hi>Warens</hi> Militia Troop being Poſted near the Cole pits lately met with a party of Rap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perees, whom they fell in with; but the Rappa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rees ſoon took to the Bog and made their eſcape, leaving eight or nine good Horſes with Sadeles and Arms behind them; two of the Horſes were formerly ſtolen from the Dutch Troopers.— <hi>Mountmelick, June,</hi> 16. Laſt <hi>Sunday</hi> night Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor <hi>Weldon,</hi> of our Militia, detacht a party of 100 Horſe, Dragoons and Foot from this Garriſon, marched them into the <hi>Kings Counte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>,</hi> two miles beyond <hi>Castle Cuff,</hi> where they ſaw many Rap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perees, but could overtake only 14 of them, which they killed, and brought off twenty eight large <hi>Engliſh</hi> Milch Cows, with ſome Horſes and Goats. — On <hi>Thurſday</hi> night he went out again by appointment between him and Captain <hi>Phillips</hi> of Collonel <hi>Earles</hi> Regiment who is Garriſoned as <hi>Philip<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>oun,</hi> they met at <hi>Newtown,</hi> and Marcht to <hi>Tullamore, Redwood: Rahan, and Linily</hi> in this circuit they Kill'd 12 Rappe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rees and brought away with them 24 Cowes which (as the former) were diſtributted among the Party. — <hi>Kildare, June,</hi> 17 Captain <hi>Bag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get</hi> with his Militia Dragoons, met with ſome
<pb facs="tcp:175672:2"/> Rapperees within two Miles of this place, the manner thus; two of the Dregoons which were the Advance Guard, came up with the Rappe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rees about midnight, who firſt Challenged our Men who they were for, they making the ſame Demand, the Rapperies replied, for King <hi>James,</hi> ſo are we replyed the Dragoons, untill their Party came up, who then fell upon them, Killed ſix, but the reſt by the opportunity of the Night ſcampered into the Bog and made their Eſcape; the Dragoons for ſome time purſuing, perceived a Perſon lying concealed in a Thicket of Buſhes, whom they ſhot at and Killed, and coming to the place found a Woman which was covered with a great many of the Rapparees Cloaths, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Enquiry was found to be a Notorious Spye, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> one for whom ſearch has been oftentimes m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Theſe Rapparees were commanded by one <hi>F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>girald</hi> as Captain, and <hi>Dun</hi> his Lieutenant, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> have made great Spoil of the Peoples goods. A party of Collonel <hi>Wolſely's</hi> Horſe who<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> detached on <hi>Wedneſday</hi> laſt to ſcour the Co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> near <hi>Balliboy</hi> of Rapparees, return'd the ne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to <hi>Billimore</hi> having Killed about 60 of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> brought with them a great many Priſoner<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 'Tis expected that our Army will move <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Athlone</hi> on <hi>Monday</hi> next.</p>
            <div type="lists_of_officers_taken">
               <head>
                  <hi>A</hi> Liſt of the Officers taken Priſoners.</head>
               <p>
                  <list>
                     <item>COllonel <hi>
                           <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>lrick Bourke</hi> Governour.</item>
                     <item>Captain Lieutenant <hi>Edward Bourke.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Coronet <hi>Daniel Greffin.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant Collonel <hi>Peter Barnwall.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Major <hi>John Dowdall.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Fard Branagan.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Robert Wolverſton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Garrat Dillon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>James Mabe</hi> Store keeper.</item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Henry Crafton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Thomas Dillon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Robert Fitz Garllald.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>William Pepper.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Luke Shales.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Thomas Arrelbould.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>John Leigh.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Thomas Tutte.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>John Kettering</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Luke Everard.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Simon Hart.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Quarter Maſter <hi>Thomas Joye.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Philip Fox.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Franeis Tipper.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Peter Dayley.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>John Brewerton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign Timothy <hi>Lenagham.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Acjutant <hi>David Kennady.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>John Bourke.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Quarter-Maſter <hi>John Gaglacy.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Henry Bryan.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Daniel Cularan</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Mark Rennolds</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Thomas Sherlock.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Valentine Ruſſel.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Owen Murffey.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Thady Crawley.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>George Fitz Gerlald.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Thomas Mac Cartey.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Thomas Smith.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Adam Archbold.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Vallentine Browne.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Captain <hi>Chriſtopher Taffe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>John Bourk.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Walter Daughton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Convers Conwar</hi> Chyrurgeon,</item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>James Barnwel.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant Collonel <hi>Thomas Corbet.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>James Linham.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Nicholas Synot.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Redmand Fitz-Garald.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>John Peirce</hi> Prieſt.</item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Mathew Evſtace.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Lieutenant <hi>Chriſtopher Barnwell.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Enſign <hi>Charles Caſtilio.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Officers,</cell>
                        <cell>54,</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Souldiers,</cell>
                        <cell>800.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Rapparees,</cell>
                        <cell>239,</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Women</cell>
                        <cell>645.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell role="total">Total,</cell>
                        <cell role="total">1738.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>And Children Innumerable,</p>
               <p>All Theſe, beſides what was Slain, which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> very Conſiderable.</p>
               <p>
                  <list>
                     <head>
                        <hi>A</hi> List of the Great Train with the Army near <hi>Athlone.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <item>Nine, Twenty-four Pounders.</item>
                     <item>Eleven, Eighteen Pounders.</item>
                     <item>Ten, Twelve Pounders.</item>
                     <item>Eleven, Three Pounders.</item>
                     <item>Six Morter Peices.</item>
                     <item>Four Hundred Wheel Carrs loaded with great Balls, Spades, and Pick axes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Fifty-Eight Cloſe Waggons with Amunition and Stores.</item>
                     <item>Twenty Cloſe Tumbrels, with the ſame Stor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </item>
                     <item>Twenty Open Waggons, with Stores.</item>
                     <item>Fourteen Shot Waggons, to carry Hand Granad<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </item>
                     <item>Two Gun Carriages.</item>
                     <item>Six Spare Gun-Carriages.</item>
                     <item>Two ſpare Limbers.</item>
                     <item>Beſides our Tinn Boats, and ſeveral Wagg<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Tumbrels, and other Carriages, that we hou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> do expect to Arrive in our Camp from <hi>Dub<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at <hi>London,</hi> and Re-printed at <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> in the Year. 1691.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
